- [Lecturer] We're staying in our interface dot DWG file.
And in this particular video, we're going to take a look
at the ribbon and ribbon panels in more detail.
Now, you can't miss the ribbon in AutoCAD.
It's that big long strip at the top
of the screen there with all the icons on it.
So when you've got a drawing open,
all of those icons become available.
They're not grayed out.
It means you can work on your drawing,
and obviously generate your designs within AutoCAD.
So what I want to show you is how all of these ribbon tabs,
ribbon panels, and things work.
So in the ribbon, by default,
you normally start in the home tab right here, top left.
And as I click on these tabs,
can you see the ribbon changes each time?
So we've got a different theme for each tab.
So the home tab, the insert tab,
the annotate tab, the parametric tab.
Now if you are using AutoCAD LT,
which is the light version of AutoCAD,
your ribbon may look different.
You will have less commands on it
because it's the light version
of the full version of AutoCAD, just so you know.
But you can see there that if I go to output,
I can plot, I can batch plot.
That's the whole idea of those ribbon tabs.
Now let's go back to that home tab on the ribbon.
Now these ribbon tabs are basically themes.
So you can see in the home tab on the ribbon,
we've got ribbon panels
such as draw, modify, annotation, layers, and so on.
Now there is a bit of repetition here.
You'll notice you've got the annotation panel
there on the home tab.
If you go to the annotate tab,
you've got even more annotation tools.
So there is repetition of the same commands
in different panels on the ribbon.
I'm going to go back to the home tab now.
Now you'll notice on the ribbon,
there's lots of little white triangles.
They're known as flyout tabs.
So if I go underneath the circle command and click on
the little flyout tab there, see the little triangle,
it'll show me all the different types
of circle commands available
on that draw panel on the ribbon.
It's the same with the art command.
You'll notice it.
There's all the different permutations and combinations
of the art command that you can use
in that draw panel on the ribbon.
Now that's incredibly useful
because I can hover over any of these.
Look, you see you've got rectangle, polygon and so on.
And the benefit is, is if I clicked on say, polygon there,
you'll notice that it's asking me
from the number of sides of my polygon, et cetera.
But note on the ribbon,
it's now defaulted to the polygon command.
So if I hit escape now a couple of times
and just cancel that polygon command,
next time I go up there,
can you see it's now set to polygon?
To get back to the rectangle command,
I just simply click on the flyout, click on rectangle.
It's now asking for the first corner point, my rectangle.
I'll just hit escape a couple of times
to cancel the command.
Be aware of that in AutoCAD.
If ever you hit a command that you don't want to use,
just hit escape on the keyboard a couple of times.
That cancels not only the command that you are using,
but any objects you might have selected as well.
So you're kind of back to square one,
and you can go back to the command you want to use.
Now these ribbon panels are incredibly useful,
as I've already shown you,
but there's some even more useful bits
in the ribbon panels as well.
So let's go to this little fly out here where it says draw.
If I click on that fly out there,
you'll notice there's even more commands available
in the draw panel.
So there's all these different commands in here as well.
Things such as splines, construction lines and so on.
But if I move away from that,
it disappears back into the ribbon again.
Now you may find that a little bit annoying,
especially if you want to use those commands
in the extended flyout part of the ribbon panel.
So all you do is you click on the little flyout arrow,
click on the little pin there, and that pins it open.
So that one now stay open
until you go to a different ribbon tab.
To unpin it, you simply click on the little blue square
where the pin is,
and it floats back into the ribbon again.
Really, really useful, quick and easy,
and it just allows you to utilize
all of the icons in that ribbon panel.
So modify, if I click there, and click on the pin,
you'll notice there that you can see
that obviously my modify commands are now there
on the screen, ready for me to use.
When I want them to go back into the ribbon,
I just unpin accordingly, like so.
Now I just want to take you through one more clever thing
on the ribbon with the ribbon panels,
and these are known as sticky panels.
Now I love these because I work
on a multiple monitor environment in my office here at home.
So what I want to do is have my sticky panels perhaps
on a different monitor, while I'm working
on my drawing on a different screen.
Now I can't do it while I'm recording the videos for you,
'cause it's all on the one monitor, on the one screen.
But here's where it gets clever.
If I click and hold on the title bar
of the drawing panel, and drag it down,
you'll notice when I release after I've dragged it down here
into the drawing area, it just drops it straight
into the drawing area.
You'll notice that the ribbon is updated.
So modify now is the left most ribbon panel
in the home tab on the ribbon.
Now this is great because it means now
that I can go to a different tab
and still have my draw tools available.
So for example, let's make my current ribbon tab annotate.
So now I can work on the annotation,
perhaps some dimensions, perhaps some labels on the drawing,
but I still got all my draw tools ready to go,
and if I hover over them, I can use them just as I would
in the ribbon at the top of the screen.
Very quick and easy.
If I click there on the flyout,
there's all my circle commands,
click there on the arc flyout ones,
there's all my arc commands like I showed you a moment ago.
So that's now floating out in the drawing area.
It's known as a sticky panel.
But here's the thing,
how do I get that back into the ribbon
now it's floating around?
I might want it to go back.
Well, all you do is you hover over the sticky panel,
the floating panel.
Can you see there's a little sort of T-shaped icon?
If you hover over that, it says return panels to ribbon.
But hold that thought.
I'm in the annotate tab on the ribbon.
Won't that return the panel to the annotate tab
on the ribbon instead of the home tab on the ribbon?
Well, why don't you try this?
Get that sticky panel on the screen,
like I've got it, and then hover over it
and click on that little T-shaped icon there,
return panels to ribbon.
Now the draw panel has returned to the ribbon,
but here's where AutoCAD's really clever.
It hasn't put it in the annotate tab on the ribbon.
If you go back to the home tab on the ribbon,
it's back where it was before,
in front of the modified panel there on the ribbon.
Very quick and easy.
Now, those sticky panels are great
if you need a ribbon panel from one ribbon tab
to be on the screen
while you're in another ribbon tab doing something else.
Very, very useful.
Now, I just want to take you through one more ribbon setting.
And for new users, when you've never used AutoCAD before,
it can completely freak you out.
Trust me, I've been in many, many AutoCAD classes
where a new user will click on this button,
and they'll suddenly go, "what have I done?
Have I broken AutoCAD?"
You haven't broken AutoCAD.
It's this little white one up here.
Can you see it?
It's a little white button with an arrow.
Now it says minimize to panel buttons.
Now if I click on it, you'll see what happens.
The ribbon changes and it's like, what have I done?
Have I broken AutoCAD?
No. All you've done is you've set up a different setup
for the AutoCAD ribbon.
That's all you've done.
It's a different appearance for the ribbon,
and you've got four different settings.
So this is the first one.
If I click on that little white button again,
there's the next one.
Where if I hover over these,
can you see there's my panels?
And then if I click on it a third time,
it disappears completely and all I've got is the tabs.
But if I click on the tabs,
you'll see there's all the information there.
when I move away, it disappears.
So last but not least,
all I've got to do now is click on that little white button
a fourth time, takes me back to the default ribbon settings,
as you can see.
So don't be afraid if you click on
that little white arrow button there by mistake.
Just keep clicking.
And on that fourth click, so to speak,
you'll be back to your default ribbon settings.