- [Instructor] We're staying in our Geometry.DWG file
and we're going to take a look at polylines,
polygons and splines.
A polyline is a group of lines
joined together to form one object.
A polygon is a multi-sided shape
and a spline is an irregular curve in AutoCAD.
And we're going to work through
each of those commands to see how they work within AutoCAD.
We're also going to work with a couple of other commands,
but you'll see that as we go as well,
because often what happens
is you work with one particular command in AutoCAD
and then you might work with another one
just to update something
with that particular geometrical object that you've created.
I'm going to roll back on the wheel
a couple of notches like so and just pan down a little bit.
So you'll notice we've got a bit of space here
in this area where we created this table
with the two circular inserts there.
So I'd like you to zoom in on that area
just above your table there like so.
So you've got a bit of space here.
Make sure you're still using the FFE furniture layer,
that one there, A700_M_FFE.
And then we're going to go to the Home tab on the ribbon
and we're going to go to the Draw panel
and we're going to click on this Polyline command here like so.
We come into the drawing area
and the dynamic input prompts us for a start point
just like the Line command.
Now hopefully, down here on the status bar,
you've still got your polar tracking running
and set at your 90 degrees
and you've still got your object snap tracking
and your object snaps on as well.
They should all still be the same
if you haven't made any changes.
Now I'm going to click about here,
click once and I'm going to drag upwards.
Now just like the Line command with the polar tracking,
you'll see there that I can drag upwards
and I can get that polar tracking line
kicking and going vertically like so.
So with that there,
I'm going to type in my 1500 and press Enter.
And that gives me that vertical segment.
Remember when we did this with the Line command?
Now we're doing this this time with the Polyline command.
So I'm going to drag across to the right now.
There's the right hand polar tracking line kicking in.
And again I'm going to do the 2500,
which you'll remember from previous videos.
So that gives us that horizontal part
of our new table that we're creating.
I come vertically down again
and again with the polar tracking,
I type in the 1500 and press Enter.
And just like with the Line command,
I can now right click and I can close.
So you'll note that that looks
just like other tables that we've drawn
but using the Line command rather than the Polyline command.
So what's the difference between a table of that shape,
a rectangular table but using the Polyline command?
Well, the Polyline command converts it to all one object.
So if I click on that now,
can you see it's all one object instead of four lines?
If I hover over it, you'll notice there, if I hover there,
it's a polyline on that particular layer.
I'll hit Escape there just to deselect it.
So what you've seen there now is three different methods
of creating that rectangular table.
Initially we use the Rectangle command,
then we use four lines with the polar tracking.
And this time, we've used the Polyline command
with the polar tracking.
So three different ways
to create a similar geometrical object.
We're going to zoom in a little now on the rectangular table
and I'm going to make sure it fills the screen like that
'cause I want you to see what I'm doing for the next bit.
There's quite a few object snaps
that we're going to be working with.
Now I'm going to create a circle first.
So staying on the same layer, Draw panel again,
click on the flyout for the circle
and you want Center Radius.
Click on Center Radius and come back into the drawing area.
Now you'll remember in previous videos,
we used our object snap tracking,
our O track or auto snap is it's name.
And what I'm going to do,
I'm going to hover here over this midpoint snap.
Remember, do not click.
I'm then going to hover here over this midpoint snap,
and again, I'm not going to click.
As I drag down, you'll see the intersection
between the two polar tracking lines.
Then left click and there's the center of your circle
at the intersection of those two midpoints.
Now the radius of the circle this time is going to be 600.
Type in a radius of 600 and press Enter.
And there's our circle.
Now the reason I've drawn a circle
is because I want to take you to the next command
that we're going to look at in this particular video,
which is the Polygon command.
Now the Polygon command is incredibly useful.
You can create polygons, multi-sided shapes,
from three sides all the way up to 1,024 sides.
Now I don't know what a 1,024 sided polygon is called.
You might need to check the internet for that.
The most I've gone to is 12 sides, a dodecahedron.
So let's have a look at this Polygon command.
It's up here on the Draw panel,
and you'll remember there's a little flyout command there
next to the Rectangle command.
So that flyout command or flyout triangle,
flyout menu, whatever you want to call it,
shows us two different commands there.
You want Polygon this time on that little menu.
And then it asks for the number of sides.
Hexagon is six sides, so we type in six and press Enter.
Now there are three types of polygon.
You've got inscribed, circumscribed and edge.
You can see edge there on the command line.
It also appears on the shortcut menu if you right click.
An edge polygon purely takes the distance
between two points and makes it the length
of one of the sides of your polygon.
Now we're not going to do that one.
We're going to use inscribed initially.
So we want the center of our polygon.
As per the prompt there
with the the dynamic input on the screen,
I'm going to hover over the edge of the circle.
You'll see the center snap appear
because we've got that object snap switched on.
Or you can just come into the center of the circle
and there's the center snap again.
Left click on the center snap
and it now gives you the option of Inscribed In Circle
or Circumscribed About Circle.
We're going to use Inscribed initially like so
and there's my hexagon.
Now as I come vertically upwards,
you'll see that I can utilize
my vertical polar tracking line,
or I could go to the right
and use a horizontal polar tracking line.
Don't go off like this or at a weird angle
'cause then your hexagon doesn't look quite right.
I'm going to go for vertical
and left click on that intersection there
with my polar tracking line.
And now we've got a nice hexagonal insert in my table.
Now that's a hexagonal insert
that is inside the circle, hence the term inscribed.
You might want it outside the circle,
which is known as circumscribed.
So let's delete that particular hexagon like so.
I'll click on it like so.
Now if you hover over a hexagon,
you'll notice you might get this weird little menu here.
This is all to do with grips
and vertices and things like that.
You can ignore that.
Just move away from any of the grips,
right click and select Erase.
Now what you can do as well
is you can in AutoCAD right click
and go back to Recent Input.
And you'll notice Polygon is on the list there,
so I can select it there
instead of going up to the ribbon if you want to.
Click on Polygon, number of sides is six,
it's remembered that from last time.
So I'll just press Enter to confirm the six.
I'll go back to the center snap, touch on the circle.
There's the center snap.
Left click on the center snap,
and this time I'm going to go Circumscribed.
So if I go vertically upwards this time,
can you see when I get that intersection there
with the polar tracking,
can you see the hexagon is outside the circle,
circumscribed about the circle?
And if I click, you can see there the hexagon
is a bit bigger than the circle this time.
So if you're happy with that, again,
you could have gone to the right using the horizontal snap
on the circle here if you wanted to going that way.
It's entirely up to you which way you go.
What I'm going to do now is select the circle,
don't need it anymore, right click, Erase.
So zoom out slightly now,
you can see I've got a nice polyline
forming the rectangular table
and there's my hexagonal insert
formed by, again, a polyline,
but using the Polygon command.
If I just roll back a bit now and pan across,
you'll notice, up here,
can you see we've got a green wall?
So you want to go past this column here
and past this group of four chairs
of the little coffee table.
You want to see this little corner of the wall here.
So there's our table we've just created.
It's up there,
sort of upwards to the right.
Zoom in a bit,
pan across a bit like that.
And as you can see, we've got some space there
above these tables and chairs.
And we're going to take a look now
at creating what is known as a spline.
Now don't worry about the layer this is going to go on.
It's going to be a wall, obviously.
It's not going to be a piece of furniture.
We can use a thing called Match Properties
to tweak that later.
Don't worry, we'll do that in a minute.
What I want you to do is go up here
to Measure on the Utilities panel.
It's on the Home tab on the ribbon,
so click on the flyout and go to Distance.
Click on Distance and zoom in on this corner a bit
and click on the little internal corner there
and come vertically up very gently.
And you'll see an intersection there like so.
When you click on that intersection,
it tells you the thickness of that wall,
which is 120.65 millimeters.
I think what we'll do,
we'll just leave that as 120 millimeters for now.
So I'm just going to click on Exit
to exit the Distance command.
So we know that our wall thickness
needs to be 120 millimeters in this particular case.
Now we're going to create a nice curvy wall
using the Spline command.
Now a spline in AutoCAD is an irregular curve
and it's using what they call NURBS technology,
N-U-R-B-S, non-uniform rational B spline.
And all it's using is a particular mathematical iteration
to create that irregular curve
based on the points that you click on in the drawing area.
Now it does sound really complicated.
It's not when you do it visually.
Let me show you what I mean.
I'm going to go to the Home tab on the ribbon again
and into the Draw panel.
I'm going to click on the little flyout here
and pin open the extra icons on the Draw panel.
Remember I showed you that in the interface for AutoCAD?
So now we've got those extra commands,
you can see we've got some curvy ones just here.
So you'll notice there I've got Spline Fit
and I've also got Spline CV.
That draws a spline with control vertices.
Spline Fit just draws a spline with points, fit points.
So that's the one we're going to click on, Spline Fit.
Come into the drawing area
and it asks you to specify the first point.
Now this is very simple to do
and it doesn't have to be exact either.
Can be a little bit abstract this time.
We're creating a curvy wall,
a bit of an artistic type wall
that separates the atrium entrance reception area
of the building from the offices
in the top part of the floor plan.
And you'll see what I mean when we zoom out in a minute.
But the first point is going to be
this little corner of the wall here.
You'll get an endpoint snap, left click
and then you're going to go up, click,
and down, click and up, click,
and down, click, and then up one more time
and I'm going to click again there like so.
I then press Enter
and that draws my nice curvy spline fit.
Now if I zoom out a bit now,
you'll see that we're kind of putting
a separation wall there,
because we've got a staircase, we've got some restrooms
and lifts, elevators, stairs, et cetera.
And what we want to do
is just kind of separate that out a little bit
so it's kind of like a little bit of a separation wall.
I'll zoom back in again now.
Now what we need to do to give that thickness,
is we need to offset it.
Now we can unpin the Draw panel.
I'm going to go to Offset here on the Modify panel.
So I click on Offset,
come into the drawing area
and you'll remember the thickness of the wall
was 120 we decided on.
So I press Enter after putting in that 120 offset distance.
I then select my spline that I've drawn, click on it,
move downwards for offset direction
and left click again to confirm that direction.
Press Enter to finish,
and you can see now that we've got a nice curvy wall
that is 120 millimeters thick.
Now it does need a little bit of tidying up.
So what we're going to do, we're going to zoom in on this end,
use the Line command
and just go endpoint, left click, to endpoint, left click.
Enter to finish.
That closes off the wall.
And then if we just do a little bit
of zooming and panning and zoom in here,
you can see we've got a little bit of a gap.
So if I go up to the Modify panel again,
click on this little flyout here next to Trim
and select Extend.
I can then click on the end of that there and click.
Enter to confirm
and we've extended that to the wall.
So if I zoom out now,
you can see that looks like it's fixed
to the corner of this wall here.
So that Extend command,
we look at that in more detail
in the AutoCAD Essential Training course,
by the way, as well.
I'm just giving you a little bit of a taster of it here
in the Learning AutoCAD course.
Last but not least, we're going to do Match Properties.
Now this is again on the Home tab on the ribbon.
It's in the Properties panel here
and you click on Match Properties.
I'm going to select one of these lines here
that forms the wall.
That's my source object.
I'm then going to select one and two
and the little line there, three.
Press Enter to finish.
And that's now all on the right leg
'cause we've matched the properties of the wall
to the splines and the little short line
that we drew earlier.
So if I zoom out now,
you can see not only do we have a nice curvy separation wall
for our little atrium area here,
but we've got a nice rectangular table there
using a polyline with a hexagonal insert
using a polygon as well.
So we've covered polylines, polygons,
and splines in this particular video.