- [Instructor] We're staying in our geometry.dwg file,
and this time we're going to take a look at polar tracking,
known as polar and ortho, or orthogonal,
as it's sometimes known.
Now I'm going to zoom out slightly
so I'm going to place the crosshair in the center of our table
that we created in the previous video,
and literally roll back on the wheel
a couple of notches like that.
And then I'm going to pan across,
hold down the wheel on the mouse and pan across,
and zoom in a little bit by rolling up on the wheel
a couple of notches, to get into this space here.
Use pan like that if you need to adjust slightly.
But ideally you want the space between the table
you've just created here and these chairs and tables here.
This is sort of space here.
Now what I'm going to do is create a rectangular table,
the same size as the one we created in the previous video,
this one here.
So see that one's a polyline,
'cause we created it using the rectangle command.
We're going to use the line command using polar and ortho
and we're going to go through creating a table
using each of those settings.
Now polar and ortho are located on the status bar,
bottom right of your AutoCAD application window.
So there's polar, it's on at the moment,
and I'd like you to click on the fly out arrow,
and change the angle increments to 90 degrees like that.
Now ortho is here, it's off at the moment,
but what we'll do is we'll turn that on in a moment.
Now we're going to use polar tracking to create a table.
Now just make sure that you are using the A_700_M_FFE layer,
it should be there already, but if it isn't,
just click on the fly out here
and make sure that you select that layer.
Click on the name of the layer
and that'll make it the current layer.
Now I'm going to go up to the line command,
like we did previously, there's the line command
on the draw panel, on the home tab, on the ribbon.
And I'm going to pick a point, say about there.
Again, I'm not worried about coordinates whatsoever,
just pick a point and Left Click.
Now as I move out to the right,
can you see I've got a zero degree polar tracking line,
that's the green dashed line,
and I've got a distance there as well
as I move along that polar tracking line.
Now we're going to create a table using polar tracking.
So move the mouse upwards,
and can you see, you get a vertical polar tracking line,
that green dashed line.
So there's my angle of 90 degrees
and there's a distance box highlighted in blue.
In that distance box, type in 1500 and press Enter,
and you've drawn a line at 90 degrees, that is 1500 long.
If you now drag the mouse to the right, horizontally,
you get a horizontal polar tracking line
at another increment of 90 degrees.
This time it's actually zero degrees,
as you can see on the readout.
In the distance box, I've got 2537, I'm going to type 2500.
Press Enter to confirm and there's another line segment,
2500 units long,
going along at that particular polar tracking angle.
If I now drag the mouse downwards from the last point,
I get another polar tracking line,
can you see it going vertically down?
At 270 degrees this time.
I'm going to type in 1500 again,
the same length as the line on the left hand side
and press Enter.
Now the good thing is I don't have to worry now
about closing out.
I can just Right Click,
and provided I haven't drawn my line segments
in a weird way, I can close back to where I started from.
So that's using polar tracking.
So I've used angles and distances this time.
Now that's great, but what happens if I want to use
ortho instead to create a similar shaped table?
Okay, so let's take a few steps back.
Now I could use undo up here.
If I use undo here, click there, can you see that?
Undoes all of those lines I've drawn.
It's quicker than selecting them all and erasing them.
So just remember you have got undo,
and because you used just the one instance
of the line command to draw those four lines,
as soon as you hit undo, it gets rid of all four of them.
Now we're going to come down to the status bar
and click on ortho here, or ortho mode as it's known.
Now you'll notice that polar tracking
turns off on the status bar when you do that.
You can only run ortho or polar, you can't run both.
You have to have one or the other.
So if ortho is on, polar is off,
if polar is on, ortho is off,
you can't have both running at the same time.
So we've now got ortho on.
What does ortho do?
Well, ortho locks me into horizontal or vertical lines.
I can't draw lines at any other angle.
So we should get the same rectangular table
but just using a slightly different drafting setting.
In this case, our ortho mode on the status bar.
So let's go back up to the line command,
come into the drawing area.
Again, it's asking for the first point of the line.
I'm going to Left Click about here,
a similar place to where I started last time.
And as I drag vertically upwards,
you'll notice if I drag from left to right,
the line only moves horizontally, can you see that?
I can only do up and down, left and right,
I can't go anywhere else.
So if I drag upwards like that and type in 1500,
and press Enter like we did with the polar tracking,
and then I drag to the right,
can you see that I'm getting the angle,
but I can't deviate from that horizontal line.
So that's going to be 2500.
Press Enter.
If I come down again,
can you see I can only go vertically or upwards.
So vertically down, vertically up, that's it.
So I type in 1500 again, press Enter.
And again, I can do that Right Click and close thing.
Takes me back to where I started from.
So you can see there
that I've got the same result using polar or ortho,
but they are very different methods of drawing things.
Now the lovely thing about polar
is you can use different angle increments.
You can use 45 degrees, you can use 30 degree increments.
With ortho, you are tied in, in essence,
to the X and Y axis, vertical and horizontal,
that's the only way you can use ortho.
So if you've got loads of straight lines to draw,
vertically and horizontally, use ortho.
If you've got lots of lines to draw at specific angles,
I would go with the polar tracking.